Guide to the Donald Bertrand Tresidder, President of Stanford University, Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Scholarships and Fellowships, Series 5
  - F.W. Van Sicklen Memorial Scholarship in Ichthyology, 1939-1948 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - George and Vivian Wagner Endowment for Maintenance of School of Education Building, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Agnes Walker Scholarship Fund, 1933-1945 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Weingarten Fellowship, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Henry Windt, Jr. SchoLarship Fund, 1927-1942 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Charles Wing Scholarship, 1944-1954 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Women's Conference Scholarship, 1937-1948 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Jacob and Mary S. Yost Memorial Scholarship, 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 7)
- Disbanding of Sororities on Campus, Series 6
  - Clippings: Sororities, 1943 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Sorority abolition, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Finance - Purchase of former sorority houses, 1943-1945 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - House mothers appointed to former sorority houses, 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Letters of approval on sorority abolition, 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Letters of disapproval on sorority abotition, 1944-1946 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Letters - National Sorority Officers, 1943-1944 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Mr. Ditz on Sororities, 1943-1944 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Dr. Tresidder on Sororities, 1943-1944 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Letters to Dr. Wilbur on Sororities, 1943 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Dean Yost on Sororities, 1943-1944 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous on Sororities, 1943-1944 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Sororities - General memos and correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Sororities - Press releases, committee reports, miscellaneous correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Sororities - Renaming of former sorority houses, 1944 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Sororities - Mrs. Jack Shoup file, 1943-1944 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Sororities - House operation, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Statements by living groups, 1943 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Statements: miscellaneous regarding sororities, 1943-1944 (Box 35, Folder 10)
- Restricted Files, Series 7
  - Faculty files, A-B (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Faculty files, C-D (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Faculty files, E-G (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Faculty files, H-L (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Faculty files, M-P (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Faculty files, R-S (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Faculty files, T-Z (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Budget, 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1948-1949 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Faculty - General (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Anonymous attack on Tresidder - faculty response, 1946-1947 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Confidential files on individual students: A - E (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Confidential files on individual students: F - M (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Confidential files on individual students: N - Z (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, 1939-1943 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees Membership Committee, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Trustee Re-organization, 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Election to Presidency, 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 5-8)
  - Presidential Search, Leland Cutler - File "A" (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Search, Leland Cutler - File "B" (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Presidential Search, Leland Cutler - File "C" (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Presidential Search, Leland Cutler - File "D" (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Candidates for Stanford President (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Presidential search file, 1942 (Box 39, Folder 5)
- Speeches, Series 8
  - "Stanford Looks Ahead" delivered before the Bohemian Club, 1942 Oct 14 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - "Men for Tomorrow" delivered at the Commonwealth Club, 1943 Sep 24 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - All-University Assembly, 1943 Oct 14 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Speech delivered before the Bohemian Club, 1943 Dec 16 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - "The Immediate Future of Stanford," report to the students and faculty, 1944 Mar 17 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - "Deceleration of the Teaching Program," an address before the American Association of Medical Colleges, 1944 Oct 24 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - "Our Post-War Dilemma," address to the Congress of American Industry, sponsored by the National Association of Manufacturers, 1944 Dec 8 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Letter to President Roosevelt, signed by twelve university presidents, on universal military training, 1945 Jan 30 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - "A Way of Life," address on Tradition Day, 1945 Feb 20 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - "My Hands to War", 1945 Mar (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - "Education and Usefulness in Life," address before Fire Underwriters of the Pacific, 1945 Mar 6 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - "The Children of California shall be our children," address on Founders' Day, 1945 Mar 9 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - "Leland and Jane Stanford, an American Success Story," speech to Stanford students, 1945 Apr 12 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - "Pattern for Living," commencement address delivered at Pomona College, 1946 Jun 4 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - "Reconversion at Stanford," address at the annual Assembly of Stanford Alumni Association, 1946 Jun 15 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - "The Next Ten Years," draft of address prepared for the Academic Council but not delivered, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - "lf I Could Start All Over", 1944 Oct 13 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Address delivered to Stanford University Mothers Club, Los Angeles, 1944 May 22 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - "The Challenge of Youth", 1944 Feb 14 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Address delivered in Detroit, no year listed, Oct 24 (Box 40, Folder 17)